newsthump.com 2019-08-30

# Privacy Policy

_Updated 24th May 2018_

At NewsThump, not only are we dedicated to trying to make you smile (or perhaps explode with rage) every day, we are also dedicated to safeguarding and preserving your privacy when you visit our site or communicate electronically with us.

This Privacy Notice (“Notice”) explains what happens to any personal data you provide to us, or that we collect from you when you are on this website or our associated shop. We do update this Notice from time to time so please do review this Notice regularly if you care about what we do with your personal data.

Due to the potentially inappropriate and world influencing content of our website we insist that all visitors be at least 18 years of age. Minors under 18 years but at least 13 years of age are permitted to view our website and purchase products from our shop, only if they have the appropriate permission and direct supervision of an adult aged 18 and over. Children under age 13 are not permitted to visit our website or buy products from our shop. So if you’re 12 or under, you should leave immediately. Yes, that means you.

**Who is collecting your personal data?  
**  
NewsThump is a trading name of Thump Publishing Limited, a company incorporated in the United Kingdom with its registered address at 40 Caversham Road, Reading, England, RG1 7BT and registration number 07849185.

**Information We Collect**

**Our Website – Newsthump.com:**

In operating our website we may collect and process the following personal data about you:

  1. Information you provide by filling in forms on our website, such as when you register for information, including to receive our newsletter.
  2. Information you provide if you submit a story for publication.
  3. Information you provide to us if you communicate with us for any reason.This personal data can include, your first name, last name, and email address.

We may also collect the following data that does not include any personal data:

  1.  Statistical data relating to your visits to our website and the resources that you access, including, but not limited to, traffic data, location data, weblogs and other communication data.
  2. Information regarding your computer whilst you are on our website, such as which browser you are using. This enables us to improve our website and to provide statistical information regarding the use of our website to our advertisers where appropriate.
  3. Since working with advertisers is economically fundamental to the continuation of our website, we do on occasion, provide advertisers with aggregate statistical information about our visitors, but (except as set out below in relation to cookies), this does not reveal personal data.

**Our shop:** ** **

When you buy a t-shirt or other product from our online shop, we need to collect and process the following personal data in order to meet our contractual commitments to you to fulfil your order:

i. Information that you provide when you place your order, including your first name, last name, email address, delivery address, billing address, and telephone number.

Without bursting any bubbles of how amazing we are, we don’t store all of our products in a massive Amazon-style warehouse ready to ship ourselves, packing them lovingly by hand and trundling off to the post office. Our shop is hosted on the Shopify platform and as such:

ii. All payment data you provide will be collected and processed by Shopify.

They will process your personal data in accordance with their privacy policy, which can be found here: <https://www.shopify.com/legal/privacy>

Further, we have some very helpful friends over at 8ball that fulfil the packaging and delivery of your order, and as such:

iii. 8ball will process your personal data including, your first name, last name, email address, delivery address, and telephone number in order to deliver your t-shirt to you and provide updates to you about the progress of your order.

They collect and process your personal data in accordance with their privacy policy, which can be found here: <https://www.8ball.co.uk/pages/legal-stuff>

The personal data we collect will always be limited to that necessary to provide the products or services that you have consented be provided.

**Use of Cookies**

We use cookies to recognise your device and provide you with a personalised experience on our website and in our shop. The information collected may include information such as the hardware model, operating system information, browser information, IP address, and device identifiers. You have the ability to opt out of cookies via the banner on our website or switch them off in your browser. This can be done by activating the setting on your browser which enables you to decline the cookies. Please refer to the documentation for your chosen browser in order to do this.

However, as we’re sure you know, cookies help us improve our website and your experience, especially in relation to the adverts you can see. We also use cookies to serve targeted advertisements from our advertisers. Advertisements are economically fundamental to the continuation of our website as we need to keep the lights on to (try to) make you laugh each day. We can’t stop the adverts appearing but should you opt out of cookies, the adverts you see may be of less interest to you, may be seen more often, and might potentially be more annoying for you than the targeted ones a cookie enables you to see.

Our third-party advertising partners use cookies to track your prior visits to our websites and elsewhere on the Internet in order to serve you targeted ads.

**How do we use cookies for advertising?**

Cookies are a key part of how we deliver advertising on NewsThump. They allow us to show advertising that is more relevant to the people who visit our site by showing you adverts that are based on your browsing patterns and the way you have interacted with our site and others. We can then show you adverts which we believe may interest you.

It’s important to understand that this website is entirely funded by advertising. Our editorial content is not influenced by the advertising we display and our writers are free to, and often do, challenge and mock the activities of companies and organisations that sometimes advertise on our site.

As you browse our site, some of the cookies we place on your device are for advertising, so we can better understand what you are more likely to be interested in. Our ad partners can then display advertising in your browser based on these interests. For instance, if you have been looking at a lot of racing bikes and accessories online, you may be shown more adverts for ill-fitting lycra all-in-ones.

The advertising techniques in use on NewsThump do not collect information such as your name, email address, postal address or phone number. We sometimes use information such as your IP address and browser type and also sometimes share some limited aspects of this with third parties for advertising purposes.

We may also share online data collected through cookies and similar technology with our advertising partners. This means that when you are on another website, you may be shown advertising based on your browsing patterns on newsthump.com. We may also show you advertising on newsthump.com website based on your browsing patterns on other sites that we have obtained from our advertising partners.

Online retargeting is another form of advertising that allows us and some of our advertising partners to show you ads based on pages you have visited on other sites.

For example, if you have visited the website of an online plumbing merchant, you may start seeing adverts from that same  site displaying special offers for taps or something, or showing you the products you were browsing. This allows companies to advertise to you if you leave their website without making a purchase.

It would be lovely if we had the option of a digital subscription, or the option of making one-off, regular or monthly contributions to NewsThump, but we don’t – as such we are reliant on advertising to fund our this thing we call ‘work’.

You can change your cookie permissions on this site here.

**Third Party Links (including to Social Media)**

You might find links to third party websites on our website. Third-party plug-ins may collect information about your use of our website or shop, say from Facebook, Twitter, Instagram, or Google +. That site may request cookies directly from your browser. These interactions are subject to the privacy policy of the third-party site.

Please be aware that when you use third-party sites or services, their own terms and privacy policies will govern your use of those sites or services. We choose and manage these third-party technologies placed on our website. However, these are third-party technologies, and they are subject to that third party’s privacy policy. We do not accept any responsibility or liability for their collection of personal data and associated privacy policies as we have no control over them. Trust us, Mark Zuckerberg never returns our calls. In addition, should you comment, share or like anything we publish on a social media third party site, any personal data disclosed by you on that third-party social media site shall be subject to the privacy policy of such third-party site.

**Use of Your Information**

The information that we collect, process and store relating to you is used to enable us to provide services or products to you that you have chosen to receive. We may use the information for the following purposes:

i.               To provide you with information you have requested from us, relating to our products or website.

ii.              Where you have consented, to provide information on other products or services which we feel may be of interest to you.

iii.            To meet our contractual commitments to you, specifically where you make a purchase from us.

iv.             To notify you about any changes to our website, such as improvements or service or product changes, that may affect our service.

We may from time to time work with third parties that offer similar or related products and services that may be of interest to you. We will always seek your express consent before sharing your personal data with such third parties and only after we have received your express consent will we share your personal data with those third parties.

If you do not want us to use your data for our or third parties you will have the opportunity to withhold your consent to this when you provide your details to us on the form on which we collect your data.

These third parties are separate to our third-party processors of personal data for the purposes of providing you with the product or service you have consented to receive.

Our sub processors are as follows:

**Storing and retention of your Personal Data**

We do not transfer any personal data that we collect from you to locations outside of the European Economic Area for any reason. All our third-party processors store and process European personal data within the EEA. Should this ever change we will ensure any transfer of personal data remains in compliance with relevant EU and UK privacy legislation.

The transmission of information via the Internet is not completely secure and therefore we cannot guarantee the security of personal data sent to us electronically and transmission of such data is therefore entirely at your own risk. Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password for any reason, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential.

We will only retain your personal data for as long as is necessary to carry out the purpose for which it was collected. Any personal data provided when making a purchase in a shop will be retained for up to six years for accounting audit purposes.

**Disclosing Your Information**

Where applicable, we may disclose your personal information to any member of our group. This includes, where applicable, our subsidiaries, our holding company and its other subsidiaries (if any).

We may also disclose your personal information to third parties:  
i. Where we sell any or all of our business and/or our assets to a third party.  
ii. Where we are legally required to disclose your information.

**Exercising your personal data rights**

If you would like us to amend, delete, or restrict your personal data or you would like or obtain a copy of such personal data please send us a message using the form below. Please note, should you request that we erase all your personal data we may require additional information from you in order to carry out this request, and as such you agree for us to contact you in order for us to fulfil your request. We may send you one final communication to confirm we have honoured your wishes.

**Contacting Us**

We welcome any queries, comments, or requests you may have regarding this Privacy Policy and/or our use of your personal data. Please do not hesitate to contact us using the form below. If you think we have mucked up and would like to complain about our use of your personal data we kindly ask for you to reach out to us in the first instance to give us the chance to put it right before doing a Donald Trump and ranting about us on Twitter, or worse still, talk to the regulator.

Without prejudice to any other rights you may have, if you are located in the EEA, you also have the right to file a complaint against us with the UK Information Commissioner (“ICO”), which is our Lead Supervisory Authority. The ICO’s contact details are:

Information Commissioner’s Office  
Wycliffe House  
Water Lane  
Wilmslow  
Cheshire  
SK9 5AF

Tel: 0303 123 1113 (local rate) or 01625 545 745 if you prefer to use a national rate number
